facinghistory.org 2019-05-08

# Facing History Privacy Policy | Facing History and Ourselves

Facing History is committed to protecting your privacy. This privacy notice, together with our [Cookie Policy](https://www.facinghistory.org/privacy/cookie-policy), sets out how we look after your personal data when you visit our website at [www.facinghistory.org](https://www.facinghistory.org/), and tells you about your privacy rights and how certain laws may apply to you.

If you have any queries about this policy or how we use your personal information, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#98e8eaf1eef9fbe1d8fef9fbf1f6fff0f1ebecf7eae1b6f7eaffa7ebedfaf2fdfbeca5c8eaf1eef9fbe1bdaaa8c8f7f4f1fbe1bdaaa8d1f6e9edf1eae1).

 **Facing History does not sell, rent, or license its customer lists to third parties. We do not sell, trade, or share any donor's personal information with any other entity, nor do we send donor mailings on behalf of other organizations.**

* #### About Us

This website [www.facinghistory.org](https://www.facinghistory.org/) (our " **site** ") is operated by Facing History and Ourselves, Inc. (" **Facing History US** ") and Facing History and Ourselves Ltd (" **Facing History UK** "). Together, Facing History US and Facing History UK are referred to in this privacy notice as " **Facing History** ", and also as "we", "us" and "our". Facing History US and Facing History UK are joint data controllers of any information we collect via this site.

The contact details of our head offices are:

#### Facing History and Ourselves, US

| 

16 Hurd Rd  
Brookline, MA 02445  
United States  
  
---|---  
  
#### Facing History and Ourselves, Canada

| 

Facing History and Ourselves, Canada  
425 University Ave. Suite 502  
Toronto, Ontario  
M5G 1T6  
Canada  
  
#### Facing History and Ourselves, UK

| 

The Old Fire Station  
140 Tabernacle Street  
London  
EC2A 4SD  
United Kingdom

[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#482427262c2726082e292b21262f20213b3c273a3166273a2f773b3d2a222d2b3c75183a213e292b316d7a78182724212b316d7a782126393d213a31)

+44 (0)20 7300 7248  

Facing History UK is registered with the UK Information Commissioner's Office under registration number ZA463293.

We also have offices in Canada, Chicago, Cleveland, Los Angeles, Memphis, New England, New York, and San Francisco. For further information, please see [here](https://www.facinghistory.org/about-us/offices).

* #### What personal data do we collect via the site?

You can visit most pages on our site without giving us any information about yourself. But sometimes we do need information to provide services that you request, and this privacy statement explains data collection and use in those situations.

We collect different information depending on how you use our site and how you interact with us. 'Personal data' means any data which can be associated with you as an individual, either directly or indirectly.

The personal data we collect via the site may include:

  * **Identity information** , such as your name, organization name and position. If you are a teacher and are using our services in that capacity, we may also ask for your place of employment, and the grades/subjects you teach.
  * **Contact data** , such as your address, area (including postal or ZIP code), email address and telephone details.
  * **Log-in data** , if you create an account on our site.
  * **Payment and billing details** , if you choose to donate to us, or if you choose to attend a paid event.
  * **Technical data** , such as your internet protocol (IP) address, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access the site.
  * **Usage data** , which includes information about how you use the site, and any communications we may receive from you.
  * **Marketing and communications data** , including your preferences in receiving marketing and other communications from us.

If you are contacting us in respect of a particular event or campaign, we may ask you questions in respect of that specific (for example, such as your goal in attending an event). We will also collect any other data that you specifically provide to us.

Our site is not intended for storing or transmitting 'special categories' of personal data, such as details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, or health information. We do not knowingly collect information relating to actual or alleged criminal offences.

* #### How we collect personal data

Different personal data is collected in different ways.

**a) Personal data you provide to us**

  * If you create an account with us, you will be required to provide your identity, contact and log-in data. You may be required to create an account in order to access or download certain materials on our site.
  * If you register to attend one of our events, or to purchase books from us, you will need to provide your identity and contact details. In the case of event registration, we may also ask some questions which are specific to the event, and if there is a charge for attending the event, we may require payment and billing information.
  * If you wish to make a donation through our site, we will ask for your identity, contact and billing details.
  * If you submit a speaker request form, we will ask for your contact and identity details.
  * When you sign up to one of our mailing lists, you will provide us with your identity and contact information and your marketing and communications preferences.

You will also provide us with personal data when you correspond with us, and if you provide us with any feedback.

**b) Personal data we collect automatically**

We collect your technical and usage data, as described above, as you use our site. Some of this data is collected using cookies, beacons and similar technologies.

For full information about the cookies we use, please see our Cookie Policy.

**c) Personal data we collect from third parties**

We occasionally obtain personal data from third party partners and collaborators and providers - but only when you have agreed to this.

* #### How and why we use personal data

We will only use your information where:

**a)You have given us permission to do so**

If you sign up to receive news alerts or our other mailing lists, we will use your **contact and identity information** to send you updates and marketing information that you have consented to receive. Likewise, we may need your **contact, identity, technical and/or usage information** to respond to a question you have asked us.

**b) We have a legitimate interest (reasonable purpose) for doing so**

We will use your information for our legitimate business reasons where our doing so will not unduly affect your rights.

We will use your **identity, contact and usage information** to keep our records up to date, and to customize our site's content to you. If you are a current or former user of our services, we may also use your contact and identity details to keep you up to date with our latest news.

We will use your **technical information** to:

  * provide and make improvements to the site, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data, and troubleshooting;
  * ensure that the site is secure;
  * analyse how users interact with the site; and
  * address any issues you may experience with the site.

We may also use any or all of the information above to administer and manage Facing History in general. If you feel that your interests and fundamental rights outweigh our business purposes, and that we should therefore stop processing your data, please let us know.

**c) We need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation**

In certain circumstances, we may need to retain or use your data to comply with regulations and/or the law.

**d) We need it to perform a contract or provide a service that you or your organization has asked for**

For example, we may need your **contact and log-in data** to enable you to create an account on our site; your **contact, identity, technical and/or usage information** to respond to a question you have asked us via our site, and your **billing and payment information** to process any payments you have requested.

Likewise, if you have subscribed to one of our events, or otherwise requested our services, we may need your contact and identity data to be able to provide that service to you.

* #### 

Personal data collected via this site is shared between Facing History US, Facing History Canada and Facing History UK.

We do not sell, rent, or lease our customer lists to third parties. We do not sell, trade, or share any donor's personal information with any other entity, nor do we send donor mailings on behalf of other organizations.

We may share your information with our trusted third-party service providers (including information technology providers such as website and mailing list hosts, and Docebo, our online learning platform provider). We will only provide those companies the personal information they need to deliver the service. They are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information and are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

If you voluntarily submit information in connection with a special project that we are conducting with another organization, we may share your information with that organization for purposes of the project.

On rare occasions, we may access and/or disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or regulation, or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) comply with any applicable law or with legal process; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Facing History; or (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the rights, property or personal safety of our employees, services or members of the public.

* #### International transfers

This site is hosted on servers located in the United States.

If Facing History UK transfers your data outside of the European Economic Area to a country which the European Commission does not deem to have adequate data privacy laws, we will ensure that such transfer(s) are in accordance with applicable data privacy laws. In respect of transfers within Facing History, we have executed a data transfer agreement giving effect to the Model Clauses pursuant to Commission decision 2004/915/EC.

In respect of transfers outside of Facing History, we either implement the Model Clauses pursuant to Commission decision 2004/915/EC or 2010/87/EU (as appropriate) with the recipient of your personal data; and/or ensure that the recipient of your data is registered with the EU-US Privacy Shield. 

You can obtain further information in this respect (including a copy of the Model Clauses) by contacting us.

* #### Data security

Facing History is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer systems with limited access, which are located in controlled facilities. When we transmit highly confidential information (such as a credit card number) over the internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

However, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we take appropriate measures to safeguard against unauthorized disclosures of information, we cannot guarantee the security of your data.

* #### Children

Protecting children on the internet is very important to us. For that reason, we do not intentionally collect information on our site from children under the age of 13. Parents can be proactive and limit web site access to their children by installing filtering software.

Children's access to the internet can enable them to visit inappropriate web sites and be exposed to unnecessary risks. In the US, the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) protects children under the age of 13 from the online collection of personal information. Learn more about COPPA at the [Federal Trade Commission's web site](https://www.ftc.gov/tips-advice/business-center/guidance/complying-coppa-frequently-asked-questions).

* #### How long we keep personal data

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for. (This includes satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.)

When we decide how long to retain personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data (and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means), and our legal requirements.

* #### Third party links

This site may contain links to other sites whose information practices may be different than ours. Facing History is not responsible for the information practices employed by sites linked to or from our web site. In most cases, links to non-Facing History web sites are provided solely as pointers to information on topics that we think may be useful to you. Since third party web sites may have different privacy policies and/or security standards, we advise you to read the privacy policies and terms and conditions of these sites before you provide any personal information.

* #### Your rights

If you are in the European Union, or if your data has been processed by Facing History UK, the European General Data Protection Regulation (" **GDPR** ") gives you specific rights over your personal data. If the GDPR applies, you have the right to:

  * require us to correct any inaccurate personal data we hold about you;
  * request a copy of the personal data that we hold about you; and
  * withdraw your consent to our using your data for marketing purposes.

In certain circumstances, you may also:

  * ask us to restrict how we use your personal information;
  * ask us to delete the personal information we hold about you; and
  * ask us to provide you with the information that we hold about you in a
  * structured, commonly used and machine-readable format.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office (“ **ICO** ”), which is the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues ([www.ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/)). We would, however, be grateful if you would contact us in the first instance so we can endeavor to deal with your concerns direct.

If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please contact us at[ [email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#264f484049664047454f48414e4f555249545f08495441195553444c4345521b76544f5047455f03141676494a4f455f0314166f4857534f545f) or by writing to one of our addresses listed above.

* #### Changes to this policy or your data

We may occasionally update this Privacy Notice. Any changes will be posted on this site, and (if you have subscribed to our mailing lists), we will also update you of any changes. We also encourage you to review this Privacy Notice from time to time to be informed of how we are protecting your information.

This privacy notice was last updated on October 10, 2018.
